GRAHAM NESSLER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

graham@grahamnessler.com 🚱 http://www.grahamnessler.com/ 📞 (215) 804-7381 (USA)

SUMMARY

I am a former history professor and published author turned software developer. I am most knowledgeable about React, React Native, Redux, jQuery, and JavaScript (ES6 and ES5), though I have worked with many other technologies, including newer tools such as Electron. I believe that the core purpose of technology is to improve people's lives, and I am continually pushing

SKILLS

CORE TECHNICAL TOOLBOX: React. js, React Native, Redux, JavaScript/ES6, ExpressJS, jQuery, JSON, CSS/SASS, HTML5 Canvas, Ember, TDD, HTML5, Firebase, Git/Github, Postgres and SQL, Webpack, Vim, Angular, Enzyme and Selenium, Mocha and Chai, Swift, Electron, Websockets

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES: Sketch, Atom, Sublime Text, Microsoft Office, Blackboard, Turnitin

OTHER SKILLS: Agile, Web accessibility/ARIA, Excellent writing skills, Proficient in Spanish, French, and English, Working knowledge of Brazilian Portuguese, Mentoring and leadership, Teaching and public speaking, Teamwork and group collaboration

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Webdriver IO Add some clarifications to guide.md

Debugpolitics.com Add hover color change for footer links and a readme

Spell check for Atom text editor Revised readme for clarification

Promise It Won't Hurt (Nodeschool course) Some small changes for clarity (to instructions)

PROJECTS

MyGov Feb 2017 to Current

MyGov is an application created in React Native that allows a user to track current Congressional bills and new laws. Using the Sunlight Congress API, the application brings in data on bills and laws including title, date introduced, date of last action, sponsor, current progress (in House Committee, passed by Senate, enacted...), and other data. This application is meant for concerned citizens (and non-citizens) to keep track of Congressional actions and to be better informed and empowered to take action on critical issues.

My core contributions: created the bill filter functionality; designed much of the React component architecture and built much of the UI from prototype; wrote all unit tests for client side code; did most of the routing and set up the drawer menu.

React Native, JavaScript, SVG, Express, Mocha, Chai

Flash Shopper Sep 2016 to Current

This is an independent solo project undertaken outside of the Turing School curriculum. It consists of a grocery list where users can enter in an item name, aisle, quantity, and a note. Users can also choose a category (such as "Bread") from a dropdown menu, which will then populate the aisle number (currently only for my local King Sooper's). The user can also sort items alphabetically and by aisle number and delete items.

React, Redux, Firebase, JavaScript, SASS/CSS, Webpack. See also my version in React Native.

(For other projects, please see my portfolio).

EXPERIENCE

Self-Employed/Freelance

Mar 2017 to Current Denver, CO

· Currently working on mobile application entitled MyGov with colleague Ian Lancaster. We aim to ship this app to the Apple Store and Google Play Store soon.

Turing School of Software and Design

Student, Front End Engineering · Aug 2016 to Mar 2017 · Denver, CO

- Completed many projects in JavaScript, React.js, React Native, HTML, CSS, and other technologies.
- Before starting at Turing, I engaged in self-study in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS from Jan. 2016-July 2016

Florida Atlantic University
Visiting Professor of History · Aug 2015 to May 2016, Aug 2015 to May 2016 · Boca Raton, FL

Taught courses in United States, Caribbean, Latin American, and global history to around 200 students

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software and Design

Certificate in Front End Engineering 2017

University of Michigan

PhD History 2011

College of William and Mary

BA History 2005